vatsnew.com 2014-02-09

# Privacy and Policy - What's New | Vatsnew.com

“Privacy can be assaulted” this statement describes how the personal information collected through the community when you register with us is protected. The terms “we” and “us” refer to Vatsnew Team which is part of the Terms of Use, which governs your use of the Site and is located here.

 **INFORMATION WE COLLECT AND HOW WE USE IT:**

 **Account Information.** Information that you provide us with as you register such as your name (First and last name or initial) and email id is stored with us. And if you wish to make your joining process you can also import your information from a third party. Your email address is used to provide you services in connection with the community and contact you on behalf of other users attempting to contact you with a message, follow and the likes. We may also use additional information like your gender, birth date and signup location (If you provide them) to display relevant updates and feed to you. You can change the information through the user account section of our community.

 **Public Content.** You can contribute to the Site in a number of different ways, including writing reviews, uploading videos and photos, participating in question and answers, tagging products, filling out your public profile, and voting on other users’ contributions. We may store these contributions (your “Public Content”), display them to other users, and use them for promotional purposes. Note that if you include personally identifiable information in your Public Content, it can be used and viewed by others. We are not responsible for the information you choose to include in your Public Content.

 **Messaging.** The Site allows you to exchange messages with others using the messaging feature and email. We may store these messages in order to deliver them and allow you to manage them.

 **Inviting Friends.** You can invite your friends to join the Site by providing their contact information, or by entering your log-in credentials to import your address book from other sites. We may store and use your friends’ contact information to invite them to join and connect with you on the Site. Your friends will always have the opportunity to opt-out of receiving further emails from us.

 **Third Party Services.** We allow you to access third party services, such as Facebook and Twitter, to share your selected Public Content with those services, and import information about who you are connected with on those other services so you can connect with them on the Site. You can always opt out on your Vatsnew account page. Some of those third party services may also provide us with information from your accounts there to enhance and personalize your use of this Site. For example, you can allow Facebook to tell us who your Facebook friends are so you can follow their activity on Vatsnew. You can also further modify your privacy settings with those other services directly. For example, you can adjust your privacy setting on Facebook to prevent your Facebook friends from sharing information about you from their Facebook accounts with Vatsnew.

 **Activity and Log Data.** We automatically store information related to your use of the Site, such as the pages you view on the Site, your browser type, IP address, requested URL, browser language, referring URL, and the date and time of your visits. We use this type of information to administer the Site and provide the better service to you. We also use this information in the aggregate to perform statistical analyses of user behavior and characteristics in order to measure interest in and use of the various areas of the Site or to manage or improve the Site.

 **Cookies.** We send cookies to your computer in order to uniquely identify your browser and improve the quality of our service. “Cookies” refer to small pieces of information that a website sends to your computer’s hard drive while you are viewing the Site. We may use both session cookies (which expire once you close your browser) and persistent cookies (which stay on your computer until you delete them). Persistent cookies can be removed by following your browser help file directions. If you choose to disable cookies, some areas of the Site may not work properly or at all. Our cookies are linked to your information, such as your name, email address and password. We enable some of our business partners to use cookies in conjunction with your use of the Site. We have no access to or control over the use of these cookies. These cookies collect information about your use of the Site, such as where you came from, which pages you visited within the Site, and possibly other sites you visit if those sites cooperate with the same third party, but do not collect your name, email address, contact information or other personally identifiable information that by itself would allow the third party to identify or contact you.

 **Feedback.** You should feel free to give us feedback, register a complaint, or ask questions about the Site. We may store your communications, including any personal information you include in them, so that we can effectively respond to you.

 **Public Content.** If you post content for public view on the Site, we may distribute such Public Content to a wider audience by sharing it (or portions of it) with third parties so that they can publish it on their own websites and media platforms. We may ask them to credit you as the source of these contributions by including your account name and profile photo.

 **Third Party Service Providers.** We may use third parties to provide technical and customer support, perform tracking and reporting functions, conduct quality assurance testing, perform payment processing and provide other services in connection with the Site. We may share information about you with them so that they can perform the services they are required to perform, but they are not permitted to use your personal information other than to provide the services requested by you.

 **Third Party Advertising.** Third parties serve some of the ads on the Site. We do not send any individualized personal information to them, but they may have access to information that they obtain through cookies or that you share with them yourself. Note that we do not rent, share, sell or trade personally identifiable information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes.

 **Aggregate Information.** We may share non-personal information in the aggregate to third parties relating to user behavior in connection with actual or prospective business relationship with those third parties, such as advertisers and content distributors. For example, we may disclose the number of users that have been exposed to, or clicked on, advertising banners.

 **Business Transfers.** We may share your information with our parent company, subsidiaries, joint ventures, or other companies under a common control that we may have now or in the future, in which case we will require them to honor this Statement. If another company acquires our company or all or substantially all of our assets, that company will possess your information, and will assume the rights and obligations with respect to that information as described in this Statement.

 **Investigations.** We reserve the right to investigate abuses on the Site, and enforce and apply our Terms of Service and Statement. We may disclose information about you to third parties if we have a good faith belief that such disclosure is reasonably necessary to (a) take action regarding suspected illegal activities; (b) enforce or apply our Terms of Service and Statement; (c) comply with legal process and law enforcement instructions and orders, such as a search warrant, subpoena, statute, judicial proceeding, or other legal process served on us; or (d) protect our rights, reputation, and property, or that of our users, affiliates, or the public.

 **MANAGING YOUR INFORMATION**

We provide a number of tools to manage the use of your information on the Site. For an overview, click here. You may receive weekly newsletter communications from us. However, despite any requests to close your account or your indicated email preferences, we may still need to contact you as required by law or on legal matters, for example to inform you of any updates to our Terms of Service or this Statement.

The Site may contain links to third party websites with which we have no affiliation. Except as set forth herein, we do not share your personal information with those third parties, and are not responsible for their privacy practices. We suggest you read the privacy policies on all such third party websites.

 **OUR POLICY TOWARDS CHILDREN**

The Site is intended for general audiences and is not directed to children under 13. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13. If you become aware that your child has provided us with personal information without your consent, please contact us at [info@vatsnew.com](mailto:info@vatsnew.com) . If we become aware that a child under 13 has provided us with personal information without parental consent, we take steps to remove such information and terminate the child’s account.

We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

 **INTERNET BASED ADVERTISING**

Google AdSense is used on Vatsnew.com. Adsense serves ads based on the content of the sites you view. As you browse websites that have partnered with Google or Google sites, such as YouTube, Google may place a cookie in your browser to track the types of pages visited or content that you viewed. Based on this information, Google associates your browser with relevant interest categories and uses these categories to show interest-based ads. For example, if you frequently visit travel websites, Google may show more ads related to travel. Google will not associate sensitive interest categories with your browser (such as those based on race, religion, sexual orientation, health, or sensitive financial categories), and will not use such categories when showing you interest-based ads.

 **How do I opt out of interest-based advertising?** If you prefer not to receive interest-based advertising, you can click the “Opt out” button at the top of this page, or click on the “Opt out” button on the Google Ads Preferences Manager Page. Google also offers a number of options to permanently save your opt-out settings in your browser. After you opt out, Google will not collect interest category information and you will not receive interest-based ads.

 **DoubleClick DART Cookie** Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on Vatsnew.com. Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to users based on their visit to Vatsnew.com and other sites on the Internet. Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy at the following URL – http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html

If you believe that Vatsnew.com has not adhered to this Statement you may write to the Vats New Privacy Office at the following address: 302/3A, Ground Floor, Prem Nagar, Gurgaon 122001 or contact via email [info@vatsnew.com](mailto:info@vatsnew.com)
